<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sinha First Lab</string>
    <string name="nslookup">nslookup</string>
    <string name="netstat">netstat</string>
    <string name="ping">ping</string>
    <string name="tracert">tracert</string>
    <string name="nslookup_desc">Nslookup is a tool that is used in the command line. Typing in nslookup followed by a space and a domain name will yield multiple pieces of information about that domain, such as the server name, IP address, and DNS (Domain Name System)server name. Alternately, if an IP address is typed after the phrase "nslookup", the it will display the domain name, and the rest of the information I specified. If you type in "nslookup /?" into the command line, it will show you all the commands that can be used with nslookup.</string>
    <string name="netstat_desc">Netstat, which stands for network status, is another command line tool. Typing this phrase in alone will bring up the protocol tpe, IP address and port number, the foreign address (name of device), and the state of the connection for all the connections on the network.  I will not provide a screenshot because I do not want to share my IP address. Similarly to nslookup, you can type in "netstat /?" for all commands that can be used with this phrase.</string>
    <string name="ping_desc">Ping is a command line tool that is typed before a domain name. What is displayed is how many packets were sent to that domain, how many were recieved, how many were lost, and how long it took to complete that process. It also displays a value called TTL (Time To Live). This indicates how much time left the packet has to live before it is destroyed. Each time the packet is transferred the TTL goes down by 1. Ping tests can be used to diagnose latency and connection issues.</string>
    <string name="tracert_desc">Tracert is a commmand line tool that stands for traceroute. Entering tracert followed by a domain name triggers packets to be sent to the target domain with minimal TTL values. These packets are sent to figure out how many routers are in the network. The packets hop from router to router, and when the TTL value expires, the information of where it is expired is sent to back to the host computer. In the picture below, you can see packets are sent to each router three times, and the time is takes to get the information from the packets back is recorded. Then , each router name and IP address is recorded.</string>
</resources>
